Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Katrin and today we have an elementary level lesson for you guys out there.
我是Katrin，今天我们为各位带来一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to talk about an interesting topic, especially for women.
今天我们要讨论一个有趣的话题，尤其是对女性来说。
We are going to the nail salon.
我们要去美甲沙龙。
Okay, so we're going to get our fingernails painted.
好的，所以我们要去涂指甲油。
Alright, so let's take a look at vocabulary preview to find out what nail salon means.
好了，让我们先看看词汇预览，了解nail salon是什么意思。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Alright so if you go to a nail salon, it's a specific place where they paint your nails,
好的，如果你去美甲沙龙，那是一个专门涂指甲的地方，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So it's a shop or a store where you can have your nails painted.
所以它是一个商店或店铺，你可以在那里涂指甲。
So they have special people to help you.
那里有专门的人帮你。
If you want to go get your hair cut, you would go to the hair salon.
如果你想剪头发，你会去美发沙龙。
Exactly.
没错。
So we have hair salon and nail salon.
所以有美发沙龙和美甲沙龙。
In this case, at the nail salon, they can't cut your hair.
在这种情况下，在美甲沙龙，他们不能剪你的头发。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time.
那我们第一次听一下对话吧。
Honey, I'll be right back.
亲爱的，我马上回来。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I told you already.
我已经告诉过你了。
I'm going to get my nails done.
我要去做指甲。
Again?
又去？
You just went last week.
你上周刚去过。
You spend more time at the nail salon than you do here at home.
你在美甲沙龙花的时间比在家还多。
Honestly, why do you need a manicure every week?
说实话，你为什么每周都需要做美甲？
Well, first of all, I like to pamper myself and my nails look great.
嗯，首先，我喜欢宠自己，我的指甲看起来很棒。
You should come with me.
你应该跟我一起去。
Why?
为什么？
I don't want to have nail polish or anything like that.
我不想涂指甲油或类似的东西。
They don't only paint my nails.
他们不只是涂我的指甲。
The manicurist will remove my cuticles, file my nails and apply at least four coats of
美甲师会去掉我的死皮、修指甲，并涂上至少四层
nail polish.
指甲油。
Yeah, sounds like something I should definitely do.
是啊，听起来确实是我该做的事。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we found some very interesting and specific words related to nails.
现在我们发现了一些与指甲相关的非常有趣和具体的词汇。
So why don't we look at those now on Language Takeaway.
那我们就在“语言要点”部分看看这些词吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so this first word is an important word for every woman to know and I know a
好了，第一个词是每个女人都应该知道的重要词汇，而且我知道很多男人也会遇到这种情况。
lot of men who get this too.
很多男人也会遇到这种情况。
It's called a manicure.
这叫做美甲。
All right, manicure.
好的，美甲。
And what exactly is a manicure?
那么美甲到底是什么呢？
Well, a manicure is a service that you get at a nail salon.
嗯，美甲是在美甲沙龙提供的一种服务。
And that means that the people at the nail salon will cut your nails and shape your nails.
这意味着美甲沙龙的人会修剪你的指甲并塑造指甲形状。
That means if you want them to be pointy or boxy and then you get them painted and dried.
也就是说，如果你想让指甲尖尖的或方方的，然后他们会给你涂上指甲油并烘干。
Okay, so they basically take care of your nails, of your fingernails, a manicure.
好的，所以他们基本上是在护理你的指甲，你的手指甲，这就是美甲。
Exactly.
没错。
And so the important thing to remember here that a manicure is for your hands.
这里要记住的重点是，美甲是针对你的手部的。
Right, so you can also get your toenails or your feet taken care of, right?
对，所以你也可以护理你的脚趾甲或脚部，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So that's different.
那就不一样了。
That's a pedicure because peda means foot.
那叫足部护理，因为“peda”意思是脚。
So pedicure is for your feet and a manicure is for your hands.
所以足部护理是针对脚的，而美甲是针对手的。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, we talked about painting your nails and that paint has a specific name, right?
嗯，我们刚才提到了涂指甲油，那种指甲油有特定的名称，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So you wouldn't use wall paint on your fingers, would you?
所以你肯定不会把墙漆涂在手指上，对吧？
So you have to use a special paint and this is called nail polish.
所以你必须使用一种特殊的涂料，这叫做指甲油。
Nail polish, okay.
指甲油，好的。
So a polish is something that makes a surface or a thing shiny.
所以“polish”是指让表面或物体变得有光泽的东西。
Okay, so nail polish is a paint that makes your nails very shiny.
好的，所以指甲油是一种让你的指甲非常闪亮的涂料。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, moving on, we talked about a manicure and there's a specific word for the person
嗯，继续往下，我们谈到了美甲，还有一个特定的词来形容提供这种服务、护理你指甲的人。
that provides this service that takes care of your nails.
护理你指甲的人。
Okay, so the job at a nail salon is manicurist.
好的，所以在美甲沙龙的工作是美甲师。
That's the person who paints your nails, okay?
就是给你涂指甲油的人，明白吗？
And so you could say, I have a favorite manicurist.
所以你可以说，我有一个最喜欢的美甲师。
Her name is Sally.
她叫莎莉。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, a manicurist, they perform a manicure and well, apart from painting your nails,
嗯，美甲师，他们做美甲，除了涂指甲油之外，
they also push your cuticles or remove your cuticles like in the dialogue.
他们还会推你的角质层或去除你的角质层，就像对话里那样。
What are the cuticles?
什么是角质层？
Okay, cuticle is a very hard word.
好的，“cuticle”是一个很难的词。
This word describes the skin around your fingernail, okay?
这个词描述的是你指甲周围的皮肤，明白吗？
So you have skin all over your body, but on your fingernail, you have special kind of
所以你全身都有皮肤，但在你的指甲上，有一种特殊的
skin.
皮肤。
And so a manicurist will sometimes push or cut the dead skin, that's the cuticle, from
所以美甲师有时会推或剪掉死皮，那就是角质层，从
your finger.
你的手指。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And if you look at your fingernails now, you will see a little thin layer of skin on your
现在如果你看看你的指甲，你会看到上面有一层薄薄的皮肤，
fingernail.
在指甲上。
That's the cuticle.
那就是角质层。
And well, apart from removing your cuticles and painting your nails, they will also file
嗯，除了去除角质层和涂指甲油，他们还会锉
your nails.
你的指甲。
And this is a verb, to file.
这是一个动词，to file（锉）。
To file, okay.
To file，好的。
So this is a word that's kind of like cut or trim, but a file is a more delicate process.
这个词有点像 cut 或 trim，但 file 是一个更精细的过程。
So it means that we kind of shave off very, very, very little at a time.
所以它的意思是我们一次只刮掉非常非常少的部分。
And so to file your nails means to make them shaped differently or to smooth them.
所以 to file your nails 意思是把指甲修成不同形状或磨平它们。
They're not cutting, clip, clip, clip.
不是剪，咔嚓咔嚓。
It's not that.
不是那样。
It's a little bit less than that.
比那要轻微一些。
And now there's also a noun for this, a nail file.
现在还有一个名词，nail file（指甲锉）。
And most women will usually have it.
大多数女性通常都会有。
It's a long piece of cardboard that has a paper that's kind of like sand on it, kind
它是一块长条形的纸板，上面有一层像沙子一样的纸，
of like sandpaper.
有点像砂纸。
It doesn't feel good when you rub it with your hand.
用手摸起来感觉不太好。
But if you use it on your nails, it will little by little just take away little parts of your
但如果你用它来磨指甲，它会一点点地去掉指甲上的
nail.
小部分。
Yeah.
是的。
Like that.
就像那样。
You usually see it, the many secretaries, you know, in TV shows, they're always filing
你经常看到，很多秘书，你知道，在电视剧里，她们总是在锉
their nails.
指甲。
Exactly.
没错。
Making them perfect.
让它们变得完美。
Okay.
好的。
So those are the words we have for language takeaway.
这些就是我们语言摘录部分的单词。
Why don't we take a look at our dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit.
我们为什么不再看一遍对话，一会儿再回来。
Honey, I'll be right back.
亲爱的，我马上回来。
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
I told you already.
我已经告诉过你了。
I'm going to get my nails done.
我要去做指甲。
Again?
又去？
You just went last week.
你上周刚去过。
You spend more time at the nail salon than you do here at home.
你在美甲沙龙花的时间比在家还多。
Honestly, why do you need a manicure every week?
说真的，你为什么每周都需要做美甲？
Well, first of all, I like to pamper myself and my nails look great.
嗯，首先，我喜欢宠自己，而且我的指甲看起来很棒。
You should come with me.
你应该跟我一起来。
Why?
为什么？
I don't want to have nail polish or anything like that.
我不想涂指甲油或做那些东西。
They don't only paint my nails.
他们不只是给我涂指甲。
The manicurist will remove my cuticles, file my nails and apply at least four coats of
美甲师会帮我修剪死皮、锉指甲，然后至少涂四层
nail polish.
指甲油。
Yeah.
是啊。
It sounds like something I should definitely do.
听起来确实是我该做的事。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now why don't we start with some phrases, some very good phrases that we found in this
那么，现在我们开始讲一些短语，一些我们在
dialogue in Fluency Builder.
这个对话里找到的非常好的短语，在流利度构建部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
This first phrase is really important when we talk about nails because it's the way that
第一个短语在谈论指甲时非常重要，因为它描述了
we describe going to the nail salon.
我们去美甲沙龙的方式。
So I can say, I'm going to get my nails done today.
所以我可以这样说：我今天要去美甲。
Okay, so to get your nails done.
好的，所以“去美甲”。
That means that you're going to get your nails cut, filed, painted, etc.
意思是你去剪指甲、锉指甲、涂指甲油等等。
I'm going to get a manicure, but that's very, I don't know, serious.
我要去做美甲，但那听起来很，怎么说呢，正式。
So you could say, I'm going to get my nails done.
所以你可以说：我要去美甲。
It's more spoken language.
这更口语化。
Okay, so I'm going to get my nails done or you got your nails done.
好的，所以“我要去美甲”或者“你美甲了”。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, the woman was talking about why she likes to go get a manicure and she said
嗯，那位女士在谈论她为什么喜欢去做美甲时，她说
that she likes to pamper herself.
她喜欢宠自己。
Okay, this is very common, especially when women are trying to talk about why they spend
好的，这很常见，尤其是当女性谈论为什么她们
money on hair and nails and clothes.
在头发、指甲和衣服上花钱时。
They say, I like to pamper myself.
她们会说：我喜欢宠自己。
To pamper means to treat very, very well.
“宠”意思是好好对待。
Okay.
好的。
So if you go get a manicure, it's kind of like pampering yourself or maybe going to
所以如果你去做美甲，那就像宠自己，或者去
a spa.
水疗中心。
Exactly, or getting a massage.
没错，或者去做按摩。
And so we could say also, don't pamper the dog.
所以我们也可以说：别宠那只狗。
He's very naughty.
它很调皮。
So a synonym would be to spoil.
所以同义词是“惯坏”。
To spoil oneself, to pamper.
惯坏自己，宠自己。
Indulge.
放纵。
Okay.
好的。
So, and well, she was talking about how they perform a manicure and she talked about four
那么，嗯，她在谈论她们如何做美甲时，提到了四
coats of nail polish.
层指甲油。
So a coat, we know that it's kind of like a jacket, right?
所以“coat”，我们知道它有点像外套，对吧？
But in this case, it means a layer.
但在这里，它指的是“层”。
So you paint your nails one time.
所以你涂一次指甲。
Okay.
好的。
You have color.
你有了颜色。
Maybe it doesn't look right.
可能看起来不对。
Okay.
好的。
It's very thin.
它很薄。
So you say, okay, I'm going to paint two coats and then you paint one more time and the color
所以你说：好的，我要涂两层，然后你再涂一次，颜色
gets darker and you paint one more time and the color gets very dark and very thick.
变深，你再涂一次，颜色变得很深很厚。
And so these are called coats.
这些就叫“coats”。
That means layers of nail polish.
意思是指甲油的层数。
And that's a special word we use when we're talking about painting our nails.
这是我们在谈论涂指甲时用的一个特殊词。
Right.
对。
So not only for nails, but if you're painting your house, maybe you need two or three coats
所以不仅是指甲，如果你在粉刷房子，你可能需要两到三层
of paint.
油漆。
Exactly.
没错。
If we have a red wall and we want to paint it white, we definitely need two, three, maybe
如果我们有一面红墙，想把它刷成白色，我们肯定需要两、三，也许
four coats of paint.
四层油漆。
Otherwise, we'll still see the red.
否则，我们还会看到红色。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Very interesting phrases.
非常有趣的短语。
Let's take a look at this dialogue for the very last time and we'll be back shortly.
让我们最后一次看看这个对话，我们马上回来。
Honey, I'll be right back.
亲爱的，我马上回来。
Where are you going?
你去哪儿？
I told you already.
我已经告诉过你了。
I'm going to get my nails done again.
我又要去美甲了。
You just went last week.
你上周刚去过。
You spend more time at the nail salon than you do here at home.
你在美甲沙龙花的时间比在家还多。
Honestly, why do you need a manicure every week?
说实话，你为什么每周都需要做美甲？
Well, first of all, I like to pamper myself and my nails look great.
嗯，首先，我喜欢宠自己，而且我的指甲看起来很棒。
You should come with me.
你应该跟我一起来。
Why?
为什么？
I don't want to have nail polish or anything like that.
我不想涂指甲油或做那些东西。
They don't only paint my nails.
他们不只是给我涂指甲。
The manicurist will remove my cuticles, file my nails and apply at least four coats of
美甲师会帮我修剪死皮、锉指甲，然后至少涂四层
nail polish.
指甲油。
Yeah, sounds like something I should definitely do.
是啊，听起来确实是我该做的事。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, Catherine, are you a big fan of manicures?
那么，凯瑟琳，你是美甲的忠实粉丝吗？
Do you get it done often?
你经常做吗？
I didn't used to, but I really enjoy them now.
我以前不常做，但现在真的很喜欢。
I think it's a nice way to relax on the weekends.
我觉得这是周末放松的好方式。
So every couple of weeks, I go to the nail salon and I get my nails done.
所以每隔几周，我就去美甲沙龙做美甲。
All right.
好的。
I think one of the words that we didn't talk about here, but it's very, I don't know, for
我觉得我们这里没提到的一个词，但非常，怎么说呢，对
men it's kind of a strange smell, is nail polish remover.
男人来说味道有点奇怪，是指甲油去除剂。
The acetone, right?
丙酮，对吧？
It's a very strong chemical.
它是一种很强的化学物质。
It is really disgusting.
真的很恶心。
Nail polish remover, you know, the word to remove means to take away.
指甲油去除剂，你知道，“remove”这个词意思是去掉。
And so when the nail polish, we want to change the color, we have to use this.
所以当我们想换指甲油颜色时，就得用这个。
It's like water, but it smells really bad.
它像水一样，但味道很难闻。
And so my boyfriend always gets angry when I use the nail polish remover because the
所以我男朋友在我用指甲油去除剂时总是生气，因为
whole house starts to stink.
整个房子都开始发臭。
It's a very strong smell and you get kind of dizzy.
味道很浓，你会有点头晕。
So that's why.
所以这就是原因。
Yeah, it goes into your head.
是啊，它会冲进你的脑袋。
All right.
好的。
Well, if you guys have any questions, any doubts, or any suggestions about this lesson
嗯，如果你们对这节课有任何问题、疑问或建议，
or any other lesson, please come to our website, EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there.
或者任何其他课程，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里见。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
♪ Music Playing ♪
♪ 音乐播放 ♪